Okay, so now we have set the path of the home for the user, okay, which, which got the
tilde symbol, MySQL dash data, we have created the directory as we have done with the
previous container and now we will give it access but make sure this time that it is very
critical for MySQL to have a redripe access for owner users which means you need to set
it to 777 at least if you are in staging or not any production environment for the MySQL dash
data container tool, okay, and now let's run the container, we need to run the database image but
with the publish port of the default SQL port of 3, 3, 6, so let's run this container, okay,
so we type Docker run and we name it my dash MySQL and this is a publish port of 3, 3,
3, 3, 0, 6 and we will mount it, we will mount it to this volume of MySQL dash data,
okay, and this is a map drive of Z, okay, which is equivalent to var library and we set the
password, this is the password and set the database my app and MySQL user which name it my user
and this is the password for my user and we use MySQL dot latest to pull down from the Docker
Hub to latest MySQL image, okay, it should search it from the Docker Hub because it will not find
it locally and it will pull it down, so it might take some time, I will pause the video till the download
and pull operations are complete, okay, now our back is a container of MySQL column latest is
successfully downloaded and pull down, so if we hear what we do next, we let's first verify that we
have two doctors, we have MySQL, okay, and it is up for 39 seconds and we have PHP Apache which
is run for 18 minutes and this is the test container that it is exited and we run it since three days
ago, okay, perfect, so if you want to run this column one more time, okay, if the MySQL has a problem,
if you see it down, it will take less than one minute, if you are above one minute then
everything is okay, everything is okay now with MySQL and you can proceed with the next step,
so let's link all of these containers together in the one network, so we will use this command
docker network to create something like a small LAN or local LAN network, so we'll use, we'll type
docker network create my dash network, okay, this is our network and let's connect both of these
created docker streets, so docker network we'll use this time connect, connect instead of
create and my network which is our the name of our network, my PHP dash, Apache this is our first
container and we'll use the same command but we'll need, we'll link my dash MySQL, okay, this is our
second duck, okay and when we run it we should see now if I want to double check that both of the
containers are in the same network, we'll type this command docker network, inspect my network
and let's double check if we have both of the container is in this network, this is the name of
my network, this is the ID of this container and this is the net mask inside of my virtual machines
which needs this PC to connect to the internet and this is the net gateway, net IP address of the
net gateway, okay, so we should have the range 172.8.0.2 goes on for the gateway, so we should
have .2 and .3, .2 is reserved for my PHP Apache, it's go from here to here, from down to up,
so this is the first IP address, it's the container IP for my PHP Apache and this is
.03 and this is the container ID for my SQL, so both of them as you can see are having the
correct IP in the same local net IP that we have set on our virtual machines and both of them
also these containers are on my network containers that we have created above, okay, that's very
so now the last thing to do here is we want to connect from our PHP container by using the
container name, I want first to connect to my PHP container, so let's clear this and connect to
let's connect to our Apache PHP container and from there we need to make update updates because
this is the Debian actually containers is running on Debian Linux, so there is no more use of the
NF that we have used in our Linux, we would use the APT tool to update this container and we install
the MySQL client because we want to connect to my database from this web server or this Apache
container, so let's update the package and come and install the MySQL client, okay, it's
operation two minutes and now we are back again, we install these times IP utilities, you
because you want to use from the IP entities that speak, we want to first pin the containers,
I will think my SQL container from the Apache, okay, so what I will do here after I install the
pink, I will type pink dash or pink my dash my SQL, pink my dash my SQL and as you can see
here from the Docker inspect comments, the previous command of network inspect, it is resolved
to 18.0.3, so network resolutions worked, I type control C to breaks operation and now we will
just make a connection by using MySQL to do which we have installed, dash actually we connect to
the host to my dash my SQL and we use user my user dash p and we skip SSL verification, we need to
type it like this or you'll get an error and this is the name of our database which is called
my app, so let's connect it and we'll type our password, okay and as you can see here
we have connected to my SQL, so both the pink is working and of course the connection to my
SQL database is worked, I hope this lesson clarifies the containers and how we can create it and
put them into the same networks and how we can interact with one container to other or connect
from one container to another one, I hope this lesson is beneficial to you and see you on the next session, goodbye.